Mahmoud Zaky Fetoh

Phone: +201022381474 github.com/zaky-fetoh

Email: zaky.fetoh@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/mahmoud-zaky-fetoh

Objective

I am a Software Engineer with 3 years of experience in software engineering, passionate about solving real-world problems and collaborating with great engineers from whom I can learn.

I have diverse experience across various disciplines, including backend development, MLOps, computer vision research, and DevOps.

Education

2021 - 2023 | Faculty of Computers and Information, Menoufia university, Egypt.

M.Sc. in Computer Vision, specialized in deep learning research, graduated in 2023.

- o Architected Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) for detecting COVID-19 in medical images.
- o Built training pipelines, validated model accuracy, and performed model comparison.
- o Monitored experiments, documented results, and writing papers.

2015 - 2019 | Faculty of Computers and Information, Menoufia university, Egypt.

B.Sc. Honors. I graduated with highest grade on my class with an Excellent honors GPA of 3.6.

- Hired as a Teaching Assistant at the same institute.
- \circ My graduation project involved creating an intrusion detection system for detecting various network attacks in software-defined networks using deep learning CIC-IDS2017 is used a training dataset

Professional Certificates.

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate [Link] AWS Certified Machine Learning - Specialty [Link]

Work Experience

$\rm Dec~2023$ - $\rm Present$

ML Cloud Consultant @ Bexprt, KSA.

Involved at architecting and implementing MLOps and DevOps projects for MENA customers.

- Job Role:
- o Architecting scalable training and serving pipelines for ML models.
- Managing AWS Cloud infrastructure across 7 AWS accounts for ML and Data teams.
- Architecting cloud-native solutions and developing Infrastructure as Code (IaC) for them.
- o Designing solutions for large-scale data processing.
- Creating and executing large-scale migration plans.
- o Designing, developing, and maintaining scalable and reliable CI/CD pipelines.
- Managing and maintaining compute clusters in AWS (ECS and EKS).
- \circ Conducting rigorous comparisons of 3rd-party tools, selecting and integrating them into the infrastructure.
- Managing the monitoring solution and create tailored alerts.
- Continuously creating and updating documentation.
- Technologies:

IaC: Terraform.

Clould Provider: AWS, Cloudflare.

CI/CD: Github Actions, Atlantis, Terraform Cloud.

ETL: AWS Glue Crawler, Glue Database, Glue Job, S3, Firehose.

MLOps: SageMaker, bentoml, Prefect, MLflow, DVC.

Micro-frontend: Cloudfront, S3, Route53.

Monitoring: DataDog, NewRelic. Container Orchestrators: ECS, EKS.

May 2023 - Dec 2023

DevOps Engineer @ n-go, KSA.

Administrating kubernetes clusters for 1M user Application.

- Technologies:

 ${\bf Clould\ Provider};\ {\bf AWS},\ {\bf OCI},\ {\bf Cloudflare}.$

Container Orchestrators: EKS, OKE. CI/CD: Jenkins, GitHub actions, ArgoCD.

kubernetes Autoscaler: Cluster Autoscaler, karpenter. Monitoring: Prometheus, Grafana, Loki, ELK, Kiali, Jaeger.

IaC: Terraform, Kustomize, Helm, Ansible.

VPN & ZTN: Pritunl, Twingate.

Service Mesh: Istio.

Jan 2023 - Apr 2023

MLops Engineer @ Susoft, Norway.

Building microservice application for Training and deploying machine and deep learning models for Sales forecasting. Performing customer segmentation to direct marketing campaigns.

- Technologies:

Model Training: PyTorchForecasting, Pytorch, pandas, Prophet, NeuralProphet.

Model Monitoring: Weight and biases, Prometheus, Grafana.

Model Serving: torchScript, Docker, K8s.

Model Registry: Minio.

Asynchronous communication for issuing train request is done using RabbitMQ

Gateway and load balancing services performed using NodeJS.

Jan 2021 - Jan 2022

Teaching & Research Assistant @ Menoufiya University, Egypt.

Teaching machine Learning and Computer vision Courses .

Frameworks & Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Python, NodeJS, GoLang (learning)

HTTP Servers Frameworks: ExpressJS, Flask.

Version Control Tools: Git, Github, Bitbucket.

Data Science: PyTorch, Pandas, statsmodels, Prophet, Numpy, OpenCV, Plotly,

LLAMA 2, PaddleOCR.

MLOps: SageMaker, Prefect, bentoml, Mlflow, Hydra, DVC.

 $\begin{array}{ccc} \textbf{Client API:} & \text{REST, GraphQL, gRPC, SocketIO.} \\ \textbf{Security Utilities:} & \text{Joi, Jsonwebtoken (JWT), OAuth 2.0.} \end{array}$

Databases: MONGODB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MariaDB.

Adminstration: CCNA, MCSA, RHCSA, Kubernetes,

Clould Provider: AWS, OCI, Cloudflare.

Monitoring: Prometheus, Grafana, Loki, ELK, kiali, jaeger, DataDog, NewRelic.

Container Orchestrators: EKS, OKE, ECS, Docker-Compose.

Infrastucture as Code: Terraform, Kustomize, Helm, Ansible.

CI/CD: Atlantis, Terraform Cloud, Jenkins, Github Actions, ArgoCD.

VPN & ZTN: Pritunl, Twingate, Cloudflare Warp.

Message Broker: RabbitMQ, Kafka.

Documentation: Swagger, I₄TEX.

Caching: Redis, MinIO.

Publications

2022 Multiscale aware classification of COVID-19 from Chest X-Ray using a spatially weighted atrous spatial pyramid pooling CNN [Link].

Mahmoud Z fetoh, Khalid M. Amin, Ahmed M. Hamad

In this paper I propose, scale invariant CNN architecture for COVID-19 classification. Proposed model based on building a scale space in each layer using Atrous spatial pyramid pooling then selecting a correct space to operate at using spatial attention module.

2021 COVID-19 Detection Based on Chest X-Ray Image Classification using Tailored CNN Model, [Link]. Mahmoud Z fetoh, Khalid M. Amin, Ahmed M. Hamad

In this paper I propose a very light-weight model as a consequence of using spatial separable kernel and depth-wise separable kernels for COVID-19 classification.

Published at: IJCI.